# Smit Panchal

Portfolio 226-899-6632 smit.1999.panchal@gmail.com

in Panchal-Smit

SmitPanchal1999

#### SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer specializing in Full Stack Web Development and Network Automation. Proficient in Python, React, NodeJS, Javascript, Ansible, Angular, SQL, GCP, Kubernetes, and Docker. With a demonstrated ability to adapt to new technologies and exceptional record of inspiring teams through effective communication and leadership.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Developer Co-Op | Nokia (Ottawa, ON)

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Spearheaded the development of a network data extraction and transfer solution using Python, Ansible, and Podman, boosted monitoring efficiency by 40%, and enhanced network performance across production sites by securely transferring critical system data.
- Developed an automation platform using React and Python, reducing infrastructure setup time from weeks to 15 minutes, increasing operational efficiency by 95%, and significantly enhancing demos, PoCs, and the sales cycle.

## Software Engineer | Rapidops Solutions (Ahmedabad, India)

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

- Led the design and development of key Salesmate CRM features, including a dynamic meeting scheduler, activity reminder, and integrated texting and calling functionalities, utilizing Angular, JavaScript, and NodeJS.
- Proficiently implemented REST APIs, Webhooks, Cron-jobs, and optimized database gueries within Microservices architecture and contributed to the entire Agile software development lifecycle.
- Successfully migrated databases of over 6500 companies from MySQL to CockroachDB to enhance scalability.
- Adhered to clean code architecture and comprehensive testing using CucumberJS, reducing post-launch issues by 70% and improving overall system reliability and maintainability.

## Software Engineer Intern | Rapidops Solutions (Ahmedabad, India)

Dec 2020 - Jun 2021

- Mastered a diverse range of technologies, including C++, Python, Linux, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, GCP, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, and many more through rigorous coursework, and consistently achieving top results.
- Demonstrated expertise through presentations and hands-on projects, such as a User Management System, an intuitive Tree View File Structure, and the HealthCard platform for managing health data online. See the projects

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Applied Computing | Wilfrid Laurier University | GPA:11.6/12 (Waterloo,ON) B.Tech, Computer Engineering | Dharmsinh Desai University | CPI:7.8/10 (Nadiad,India) Sep 2022 - Dec 2023

Sep 2017 - Apr 2021

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages** C#, C++, Java, Python, Shell Scripts, Bash

Web Technologies HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript

**Frameworks** Rest APIs, Microservices, gRPC, Angular, NodeJS, Kubernetes, Django

MySQL, CockroachDB, Oracle, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Redis **Databases** 

Git, Linux, Ansible, Postman, Cucumber, Docker, Jenkins, Android Studio Software, Tools & OS **Cloud Platforms** Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Azure

#### **PROJECTS**

## CloudDriven - Personal Digital Storage and Secure Sharing | MEAN Stack, Heroku, AWS

- A cutting-edge Personal Storage solution enables users to upload, download, and share files securely.
- Incorporated a user-friendly folder structure and introduced QR code functionality for effortless file sharing.

## Helping Hands - Emergency Help and Safety System | Android Studio, Java, Firebase

- A life-saving Android application, dedicated to providing immediate assistance during critical situations.
- Empowered users to promptly communicate their emergencies and automatically notify nearby volunteers with live user locations via Google Maps, enhancing real-time responses and fostering community support.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

## **Hackerrank Intermediate Problem Solving Certified**

Hackerrank

Acquired advanced proficiency in Data Structures like HashMaps, Stacks, Queues, and Algorithms.

## C & C++ Programming Language Certification

Certificate

Completed C & C++ programming languages course by an ISO 9001-certified company, Itronix Solutions.

## CodeChef Online Competitive coding platform - 3 stars (1615 rating)

CodeChef

Participated in online competitive coding contests and solved over 100 problems to attain top ratings.